# Jaya Lakshmi CR

Adaptable Data Scientist with 3 and half years of experience. Skilled in interpreting and analyzing data for retailers, handling unstructured data and training the machine learning algorithms to classify and learn to detect patterns and useful information from them.

# (+91) 80123 22542

chandru.dhaya@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/jaya-ramachandran-07892490/

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Capgemini India Pvt Ltd — Associate Consultant

June 2018 - Present

Working on building a cognitive document processing solution for the financial industries that involve large number of documents that needs to be submitted throughout the process. The solution aims to reduce the amount of manual effort required in each stage thereby reducing the time involved, reducing the chances of manual errors and the labor cost involved. The solution is built using Python and the machine learning packages like Numpy, Scipy, Scikit-learn, Pandas and the image processing packages like OpenCV as the base and Neo4j for storing the extracted information.

# **Coimbatore Institute of Technology** — Assistant Professor

Nov 2017 - May 2018

Taught Data Mining for M.Sc. Software Systems students for a semester.

# Oracle India Pvt Ltd — Data Analyst

June 2016 - Nov 2017

Helped with the development of Price Optimization, Forecasting, Outlier Analysis and Market Basket Analysis with respect to Retail Industry. Done benchmarking Analysis for various international retailers.

# Oracle India Pvt Ltd — Intern

June 2014 - Nov 2014 and Dec 2015 - May 2016

Worked on Customer Behavior Analysis to alter the pricing mechanisms effectively and Markdown Optimization for adjusting the Markdowns given by the retailer. Done Size Profile Optimization for multiple retailers

### **Core Competencies**

- > Python, SQL and R Programming language
- Knowledge in using AWS and Parascript Form Definition Studio
- Data Analytics
- Machine Learning Problems Supervised Learning, Clustering, Anomaly Detection, Neural Nets
- Machine Learning Algorithms Regression Algorithms, Instance based algorithms, Regularization algorithms, Decision Tree algorithms, Bayesian algorithms, Clustering algorithms, Association Rule Learning algorithms, Artificial Neural Networks

#### **SKILLS**

- Power user of Excel, Python, R and SQL
- Knowledge in using Analytics to find conclusions
- Strong communication and creative problem-solving skills
- Experienced in at using Neo4j, Oracle 11g, MS Access databases

#### **EDUCATION**

Coimbatore Institute of Technology, Coimbatore — Master's in Software Engineering (8.14/10 CGPA).

July 2011 - May 2016

Avila Convent Matric. Hr. Sec. School, Coimbatore — *HSC* (86%).

June 2010 - March 2011

Avila Convent Matric. Hr. Sec. School, Coimbatore — *SSLC* (92%).

June 2008 - March 2009

#### **ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- Conducted HTML Workshop for school students in Young Mind Crea Soft Camp 2015
- Won 3rd prize in Science Fair conducted worldwide for Oracle RGBU employees